Welcome to the 2026 release wave one
launch edition of Business Central. This
session is about the enhanced
subscription billing analytics
and more specifically the value in this
is that we are unifying the user
experience for the Power BI reports on
subscription billing to match the other
apps so it just feels the same.
Um
Yeah, so that's what we did. Actually,
we did one more thing. We also added
better demo data in the subscription
billing area. So if you're demoing both
subscription billing with analysis mode
views or with Power BI,
both will light up with some some better
data stories. So let's let's get
started.
For Power BI,
um the subscription billing app I think
have almost 15
pages and we completely reworked the UI
so that it it it feels it has the same
look and feel as as the other eight
Power BI apps.
Um
Here are all the reports that got
updated and I think I have highlighted a
few. So here is the subscription billing
overview in version 27 and version 28.
You can kind of hopefully recognize the
overviews in in the new layout
or redesign. Um I'll just show you a few
of these examples. So the revenue year
over year growth has been modified
and I want to highlight a few things.
First of all, you can see that we have
um
added the type of visual but also adding
tooltips. So it's actually the same
information you had before but just a
little bit more slick. You also have a
navigation visual down here. So if you
go
to different packages and just navigate
and and choose these
um
bars instead of going to the filters,
everything will will will filter to
that. And then we have added these
visual indicators um
in the matrix so that you also get a
good sense of
uh of not only the numbers, but the size
of things.
For revenue analysis, the same thing.
Oh, let me just go back here. We just
added again navigational visuals. So,
when you do that
um
tree analysis, you can also instead of
filtering, you can filter
uh with these. There's plenty of room on
the report for that.
Uh for revenue development, the same
idea as as before, where we're moving
into a
slicker, in my opinion, slicker visual.
Again, with with tooltips uh for the
details. Same idea with the
um with the churn analysis, where you
have that um easy to filter visuals.
Um then revenue by item, we're
introducing uh since in the other apps
for revenue, we have these um bubble
charts, where you can go into more
details about like two-dimension
profitability
um
uh with the with monthly recurring
revenue on one axis and in in many of
these uh profitability, it's it's it's
it's mapping two metrics against each
other, and the size of bubbles is now
showing you something. So, that's that's
what we're bringing into the app from
the other Power BI apps.
Uh similarly, in the in in the work we
did in the last two release waves on the
other apps, we introduced map visuals,
so that's also uh introduced here. So,
you can now see your revenue by customer
also by geography.
Yeah, and I'll just show you a few
examples of the
It's It's the same look and feel. So,
total contract value year-over-year.
Uh again for code So, total contract
value analysis and so on. So, I I think
you get the picture. I'll skip the rest.
You can see all of the the new things
either installing the app or looking
into the documentation.
And then I mentioned that we added demo
data for subscription billing. We added
more customer contracts, more vendor
contracts, more transactions, so that
hopefully both the Power BI apps but the
in-client analysis will make it possible
for you to tell some more data stories.
If you want to learn more about demo
data, there's a full session on that.
So, so go and check out the link in the
presentation here for for that extended
uh session on demo data.
If you want to learn more about
subscription billing analytics, uh just
search for subscription billing app in
our power in our documentation. That
will take you to the documentation where
you can read like usage scenarios and
and see all the updated Power BI
reports.
And uh if you're interested in this
topic, you might also be interested in
in some of the other analysis or
data-related sessions we have. So, uh
anything from enhanced sales analytics
all the way down to enhanced analysis
mode. Go check the links in the
description here and hopefully uh go and
visit some of these other sessions that
are related to analytics.
That's all. Stay tuned. If you don't
know the Business Central resources, so
they are coming after my goodbye because
this video is is now over. I hope you
have a great launch event and uh you
another day. Bye.
We have compiled a number of general
resources that we believe are key both
for partners but also Business Central
customers. Most Some of these are
partner, some of them are also for
customers. So, the first one is
called aka.ms/bcall.
This is a partner resource for that
contains lists of every other aka link
that is needed for you to understand
anything about both the Business Central
product but also processes around it.
We call these aka links because they're
called aka.ms and then for forward slash
something. And with Business Central
links we all always prefix with BC and
then something.
The next one is our partner network
social media for for Business Central
partners Viva Viva Engage. So,
aka.ms/bcvivaengage
is where you go and interact with other
partners. It's not open for customers.
So, this is where you can ask the
questions, interact with the product
group, interact with with with each
other
in a in a closed network.
Second link a third link is for both
partners and customers we are called
office hours. So, office hours is
something we do once or twice a month
from the product group engaging with the
community about new features or things
we want to discuss. aka.ms/bcofficehours
is the is the place where you go to find
out about upcoming events.
These are recorded. I believe the
recordings are available only to
partners but the live events are
available to customers as well.
Fourth link is YouTube our YouTube
channel. I'll talk about that
in the next slide and LinkedIn in the
next slide.
And then finally for for Microsoft
partners,
the BC's aka.ms/bc
partner portal is where you get
a lot of the resources as a partner such
as compete decks,
pitch decks, and a lot of other
resources.
For LinkedIn, this is our product
group's LinkedIn profile. We have 30K or
more followers. So, both partners and
customers This is the place where we
from the product group put in news and
small bits of information outside the
official channel. So, follow us
on LinkedIn to learn what's happening
right now
in in this in the around the product.
And then
also on our YouTube channel, this is
where you're probably watching this
aka.ms/bc
YouTube. We put in not only these launch
editions twice a year, but also
Copilot and AI video shorts, tips and
tricks, technical deep dives, under the
hood.
We even have this What's Cooking where
we put little nuggets of of videos out
for new features that are even coming in
on the YouTube channel before they're
coming in the release notes. So, watch
and maybe
bookmark us on YouTube. And also notice
all the playlists. So, the the content
is also organized in areas, not only all
the videos. So, if you have an area that
has special interest such as analytics,
you can find an
a playlist and kind of see all the
content related to that.
And that's it. That is truly it. We
won't
There will be no more. So, thank you for
watching all the way to the end.
And again, have a great day. Thank you.